雪菲德营区 夏威夷，1941年
马吉欧，你好
Hey, Maggio! Hello!
你好，普威特
Hiya, Prew.
你怎么会来这里？  我从薛福特堡被调过来
What are you doing here?   Transferred from Fort Shafter.
你离开号角兵团了吗？
You quit the Bugle Corps?
为了来这里？  不是我自己选的
For here?   I didn't pick it.
你错了！他们可以把这个军团 还给卡斯特将军
You made a mistake. This outfit they can give back to General Custer.
上尉还没进办公室
Captain ain't in yet.
我四处去看看
I'll look around.
你以为你在干什么？
What do you think you're doing?
你叫什么名字？  普威特，从薛福特堡调来
What's your name?   Prewitt. Transfer from Fort Shafter.
我听说过你  我也听说过你，上士
I heard about you.   I heard about you too, sergeant.
这里是步兵团 你在太阳下山前不该玩乐的
This is a rifle outfit. You ain't supposed to have fun before sundown.
把球杆收起来，跟我来
Put up your cue and come along.
葛兰昨天去过医院 你的报告写好了吗？
Grand went to the hospital yesterday. Did you do the report?
我还没有时间写，上士  你是文书官
No time, sergeant.   You're the company clerk.
医官很晚才将病历送来 我会写的
The medics didn't bring back the sick book till late. I'll do it.
多谢！我已经替你写好了
Thanks, I already done it for you.
你是薛福特堡最棒的号手 也是全岛最棒的
You're the best bugler at Shafter. On this whole island.
那倒是事实
That's true.
我同情你，但站在我的立场 我还是不了解你
I feel for you, pal. But from my position, I can't quite reach you.
立正！
Hut!
稍息  早安，长官
At ease.   Morning, sir.
有什么特别的事吗？ 我只有几分钟时间
Have anything special for me? I only have a few minutes.
是的，长官，有新兵报到  是的，进来
Yes, sir. New man here.   Oh, yes. Come in.
长官，罗勃普威特大兵 向连长报到
Sir, Private Robert E. Lee Prewitt, reporting to the company commander.
稍息！服役纪录呢？
At ease. Where's that service record?
生于肯塔基州 在维州梅尔堡入伍，第一号手
Born in Kentucky, enlisted first at Fort Meyer, Virginia. First bugler.
我通常会跟新报到的人谈谈
I make it a policy to talk to my new men.
本军团的运作很顺利
I have a smooth running outfit.
如果我欣赏某位士兵 他便能迅速升任无委任状士官
If I like a soldier, he can get to be a non commissioned officer quick.
但他得让我看看他够精明
But he has to show me he's got it on the ball.
你在号角兵团惹了什么麻烦？
What was your trouble in the Bugle Corps?
没有惹麻烦，长官  那么你为何请调？
No trouble, sir.   Why did you transfer?
那是个人因素
It was a personal matter.
你有什么想问的吗？上士  是的，长官
Something you want to ask, sergeant?   Yes, sir.
普威特，你原是下士
Prewitt, you was a corporal.
你却自动降为大兵 调至步兵团，为什么？
You took a bust to buck private to transfer to an infantry outfit. Why?
是因为你喜欢步行 还是你受不了吹号角？
Because you like to hike, or because you couldn't stand to bugle?
完全是个人因素
It was a personal matter.
这由连长决定  是怎么样？
Company commander decides that.   Well?
我担任了两年的第一号手 但军士长的朋友调了进来
I was first bugler for two years. The topkick's friend transferred in.
第二天他便成了第一号手
The next day he was made first bugler.
我吹号的技巧比他好  你因此而离开？
I was a better bugler.   You left because of that?
或许是有些不太理智  他的情感受到伤害
Maybe it ain't sensible.   His feelings were hurt.
他们现在给我们的人手是这样的
The kids they send us now!
我们会恢复你的官阶 或许还让你升官
We'll get your stripes back, maybe an extra one.
你知道你为何在参谋本部？  不知道，长官
You know why you're in G Company?   No, sir.
我利用了一些关系 我现在是军团的拳击教练
I pulled a few strings. I'm the regimental boxing coach.
是的，长官
Yes, sir.
两年前，你就应该打赢康纳斯的
You should have won your fight with Conners 2 years ago.
谢谢你，长官
Thank you, sir.
去年我们在决赛时败北 但今年我一定要获胜
We lost the finals last year, but I mean to win this year.
我需要中量级的好手
I need a top middleweight.
很抱歉，长官！我已不打拳了  不打拳？为什么？
I'm sorry, sir. I quit fighting.   Quit fighting? What for?
一年多前，或许你听说过 迪西威尔斯的事
Over a year ago. Maybe you heard about what happened with Dixie Wells?
你是指受伤的那家伙？  是的，长官
You mean that fellow that got hurt?   Yes, sir.
我是听说过 我能了解你的感受
I heard about that. I can understand how you feel.
那种事难免会发生  他是我不打的原因，长官
Those things happen.   That's why I quit, sir.
你不能因为死了一个人 就说“停战”
You can't say "stop war" because one man died.
我们的拳击课程 是最能提振士气的
Our fighting program is the best morale builder we have.
军团已经有一位走音的号手
I've got a mighty sour company bugler.
你喜欢这工作吗？  如果要打拳就不喜欢
How'd you like the job?   Not if it means fighting.
你打算取得独行侠的声誉吗？
You trying to acquire a reputation as a lone wolf?
军队里不能有个人主义存在
In the Army, it's not the individual that counts.
军团不会对你施加压力
We won't put pressure on you in my outfit.
你只要不犯错就行了
Just don't make any mistakes, that's all.
我要进城去，还有事吗？
I'm going into town. Anything else?
军团的预算报告要交了  你写吧
The company fund report is due.   You do it.
没有其他了？  不是的，长官
Is that all?   No, sir.
由你全权处理 下午如果有事，代签我的名字
You fix it up. If there's anything this afternoon, sign my name.
我不会回来了  是的，长官
I won't be back.   Yes, sir.
如果不是我在后面替他打理 他早就完蛋了
He'd strangle in his own spit without me to swab his throat.
走吧！
Come on.
你已从军五年？五年半？
You been in the Army five years? Five and a half?
你不认为是时候 该学聪明些了吗？
Don't you think it's about time you got smart?
你拒绝了炸药荷姆斯 等于是自找死路
By turning down Dynamite Holmes, you put your head in a noose.
当拳击手很轻松 你最好学学怎么当兵
Things are soft for a boxer. You'd better know how to soldier.
我当得和任何人一样好
I can soldier with any man.
这里快变成夏威夷皇家饭店了
This is getting to be like the Royal Hawaiian Hotel.
她是谁？  她是荷姆斯上尉夫人
Who is that?   She's Captain Holmes' wife.
你会被逼赛拳，因为荷姆斯上尉 想成为荷姆斯少校
You'll fight, because Captain Holmes wants to be Major Holmes.
他认为赢得拳赛就能升官
He thinks he'll make it with a winning team.
就算不为他，也为了我 我的工作就是让他高兴
If not for him, for me. My job is to keep him happy.
他愈高兴，就愈不会来烦我
The happier he is, the less he bothers me...
而且我就会把他的军团 管理得更好
...and the better I run his company.
我们清楚我们的立场吧？  我知道自己的立场
We know where we stand, don't we?   I know where I stand.
不依他的人将一事无成  在拓荒时期或许还可以
A man don't go his way, he's nothing.   In the pioneer days, he could.
但是现在你必须照章行事
But today you got to play ball.
列瓦！我能不能走进来之后 看到你用双手在工作呢？
Leva! Can't I walk up and find you working with both hands?!
你们付我的薪水根本不够  替这个人准备些用品
Not on what you people pay me.   Draw this man some supplies.
寝室在顶楼 把你的袋子放好后再回来
Squad room is on the top floor. Leave your bags and come back.
列瓦会帮你 可以替你省下四，五趟路
Leva'll help you. Save you four or five trips.
谢谢
Thanks.
我不喜欢浪费体力 你会需要你的体力的
I hate to see energy wasted. You'll be needing yours.
他看来是个好人  我了解他这种人！他是死脑筋
Looks like a good man.   I know his type. He's a hard head.
大热天她还穿毛衣  我想她一定冷若冰霜
Her and them sweaters.   I bet she's colder than an iceberg.
不会的，军士长，她很懂世故的
Not her, Top. She knows the score.
是吗？
Is that right?
我在布里斯堡听说很多事  是吗？
At Fort Bliss, I heard plenty.   You did, huh?
我认识她的伴侣 你不用告诉我了
I know the guys she played around with. So don't tell me.
我没有！是你在告诉我！
I ain't. You're telling me.
早安，上士  早安，夫人
Good morning, sergeant.   Morning, ma'am.
我来找我丈夫  他到城里公干去了
I'm looking for my husband.   He's in town on business.
他说有东西留给我 你知道吗？
He was to leave some things. Do you know about them?
不知道，夫人！我能效劳吗？  不用了，谢谢
No, ma'am. Anything I can do?   No, thanks.
我很乐意效劳的，夫人
I'd be glad to help, ma'am.
我丈夫告诉我很多你的事，上士
My husband's told me a lot about you, sergeant.
他说你做事的效率很高  是的，夫人
He says you're very efficient.   Yes, ma'am.
你为何如此有效率？上士  因为我天生聪颖，夫人
What makes you efficient, sergeant?   I was born smart, ma'am.
我喜欢这个说法 再见了，上士
I love that. Well, goodbye, sergeant.
她可真是啊，对吧？  真是什么？
Man, she sure is one, ain't she?   One what?
真是尤物  我看过更美的
One woman.   I've seen better.
凯伦
Karen!
对不起！我回来晚了  没有关系
Sorry I'm late.   It doesn't matter.
我在军官乐部 被史莱特将军缠住了
I got tied up with General Slater at the Officer's Club.
将军说了些什么？
What did the general have to say?
他说要成功！战时要成功 和平时更要成功
Success, he said. Success in war, success in peacetime.
对我的升官却一句也没提
And not a word about my promotion.
有时我觉得他想降我职
Sometimes I think he's waiting to ship me down.
少去奉承将军们 多跟你的军团在一起
Spend less time buttering generals and more time with your company.
军团可以照顾自己
The company takes care of itself.
我今天去找过你  我到卡纳欧黑办事
I looked for you, today.   I had some business at Kaneohe.
你不介意吧？  当然
That was all right, wasn't it?   Of course.
我没有权利过问 那是我们同意的
I have no right to inquire. That was our agreement.
为什么要提起这件事？
Why bring it up?
我可不是你 认为的那种笨女人
I'm not as stupid as you think all women are.
这话什么意思？
Now, what does that mean?
你又在指控什么了？  没事
What's the accusation now?   Nothing.
你跟多少女人出去 也不干我的事，对吧？
It's none of my business how many women you go out with, is it?
但我希望你能诚实
But I wish you were honest.
为什么要隐瞒？ 我们之间已经这样了
Why hide anything? The way things are between us now?
你凭什么一直这样指控我？
What right have you to always accuse me?
凭什么？
What right?
你还要再翻旧帐吗？ 我还得忍受多久？
Are you going back to that again? How long before I live that down?
我得跟你说几次那是意外？
How many times do I tell you it was an accident?
拜托你，唐纳
Please, Dana.
我要睡了！请离开我的卧房
I'm going to bed. Please get out of my bedroom.
荷姆斯上尉说你不想打拳
Captain Holmes says you don't want to fight.
没错  我请你喝杯啤酒而且谈一谈
That's right.   Let's buy you a beer and talk.
我们是军团的拳击手  我猜也是
We're the company boxers.   I figured.
我真希望他在我家乡的弹子房
What I would give to have him in the pool room in my home town!
如果你跟以前一样打得好 我们就赢定了
If you box as good as before, we'll be a cinch.
别忘了！区冠军还可以 放十天的假
Don't forget: Division champs get ten day furloughs, son.
我是艾克葛罗维奇 是你的排长
I'm lke Galovitch. Platoon guide of your platoon.
别以为你很强悍，普威特
Don't think you're tough, Prewitt.
现在不说话 到野外可就要喊救命了
You no talk now, but in the field you sing different.
如果他不想打拳 就用不打
He don't have to fight if he don't want to.
我们正在打撞球！走开
We're playing pool. Take off.
你讨打吗？马吉欧 你最好少管闲事
You want busted head, Maggio? Then keep your big nose out.
下礼拜开始集训
Training starts next week...
我已告诉过荷姆斯 现在我告诉你，我不打拳了
Look, I told Holmes and I'm telling you. I ain't fighting.
我已经不打拳了 你们可以尽管威胁我
I quit fighting! You guys want to put the screws on, go ahead.
你想做什么，我能忍受  好了，普威特
I can take anything you dish out.   Okay, Prewitt.
谢谢
Thanks.
我不喜欢看到好人被欺负
I hate a good guy to get it in the gut.
习惯吧！小子 你在死之前，会常见到的
Get used to it, kid. You'll see a lot of it before you die.
你真够胆，对吧？
You don't scare easy, do you?
军队有规定我一定要打拳吗？
Army regulations say I got to box?
本军团的每个拳手都是 无委任状士官
Every boxer in this outfit's a non com.
你不曾见过他们 聚集在一起给某人特别训练
You've never seen them get together and give a man the Treatment.
你怎么会称她小妞？ 她已经四十五岁了
What do you mean "chick"? She's forty five.
对你来说还太年轻  我比你好多了
Still too young for you.   I'm a better man than you.
别忘了  我不会忘的
Don't forget it.   I won't forget it.
华登是怎么回事？ 我不了解他
What's the deal with Warden? I don't figure him.
他不像别人
He ain't like the others.
他会对你很严厉
He'll make it tough on you.
但他会划定一条公平界线 而且会谨守份际
But he'll draw a line he thinks fair and won't cross it.
现在很少有这种军士长了
You don't see many topkicks like him no more.
他在十五军团时 在上海作战
He was with the 15th in Shanghai when they saw action.
连在菲律宾的我 也听说过他的战绩
I heard about it in the Philippines.
我只知道 他是我见过最好的军人
All I know is he's the best soldier I ever saw.
答数！继续答数  1，2，3，4
Count, keep count!   One, two, three, four.
跟上脚步，普威特
Get in step, Prewitt!
这是出操，可不是野餐 快跟上脚步
This is a drill, not a picnic. Get in step!
普威特！向前一步，走！
Prewitt! One step forward, march!
你的步法好像喝醉的鸟一样 我来教你出操！留在原地
You march like a drunken bird! I'll teach you to drill. Stay here.
小队解散！
Platoon dismissed!
士兵！向右转
Detail, right face!
组合武器！预备！开始
Assemble your weapons. All right, start.
来福枪是你最好的朋友
A rifle's your best friend.
如果在战斗中卡住了 可能会让你丧命
If it jams in combat, could mean life or death.
你一定得学会蒙着眼 也可以组合与拆解
You got learn to strip 'em down and put 'em back together blindfolded.
你的后瞄准器不准 你在瞄准三百码时会误失五十尺
Your rear sight's off! You'd be 50 feet off target at 300 yards.
士兵不了解他的武器 就会发生这种状况
That's what happens when a soldier don't know his rifle.
跑七圈！把枪举在胸前
Seven laps! Keep the rifle at high port!
懂了吗？普威特 或许再七圈你就懂了
Wide open, huh, Prewitt? Maybe seven more laps'll teach you.
你疯了？我看到你做的事了
Are you crazy? I saw what you did.
她是个大麻烦 别再想你在想的了
She's trouble. Stop what you're thinking.
你想在李汶渥斯监狱终老吗？
You wanna wind up in Leavenworth?
我赶不上归营号了
I won't be back in time to take retreat.
或起床号  是的，长官
Or reveille, either.   Yes, sir.
只管工作没有娱乐，上士 你只会做文书工作
All work and no play, sergeant. All you do is sweat over papers.
除了工作还有其他事情
There are other things beside work.
多多出去走走，华登  我一直在考虑这件事
Get out more, Warden.   I've been considering it.
我要走了 事情就留给你处理，上士
I'm going. I'm leaving it in your care, sergeant.
你回来时全部都会做好，长官
It'll be here when you get back... sir.
原来是华登上士
Well, if it isn't Sergeant Warden.
快进来！你会被两淋湿
Step inside or you'll get wet.
我已经湿透了
I am wet.
如果你想找上尉，他不在家
If you're looking for the captain, he isn't here.
假设我找的不是他呢？  他还是不在
And if I'm not looking for him?   He's still not here.
我是要找他 你知道他在哪里吗？
I am looking for him. Do you know where he is?
我不晓得 或许他又“到城里公干”
I haven't any idea. Perhaps he's "in town on business."
前几天你是这么说的，对吧？
That's how you put it the other day, isn't it?
我有些重要文件得请他签名
I got some papers it's important for him to sign.
我打电话到俱乐部试试  别那么做
I'll try phoning him at the club.   Don't do that.
我不想打扰他的酒兴
I don't disturb a man who's drinking.
我自己也想喝一杯
I could use a drink myself.
你要邀我进去吗？
Do you wanna ask me in?
酒就在那边柜子里，上士
The liquor's there, sergeant. In the cabinet.
你冒了极大的危险 我的女佣随时可能会到家
You're taking an awful chance. My maid is liable to be home any time.
星期四是她的公休日
Thursday's her day off.
你一切都想好了，是吗？  我试着，这个职务必须如此
You think of everything, don't you?   I try. In my position, you have to.
这真的很重要吗？  是的，但明天也可以
Are these really important?   Yes. But tomorrow's okay.
我还有副本，很容易就能处理
I got copies. It'll be easy to fix them.
我喜欢，上士 你很有自信
I like that, sergeant. You have confidence.
这也是我不喜欢你的地方  这不是自信而是诚实
It's also what I dislike about you.   It's not confidence. It's honesty.
我不愿意见到美人独守空闺 浪费了
I hate to see a beautiful woman go to waste.
你是说浪费吗？
Waste, did you say?
我可以告诉你很多跟这有关的事
There's a subject I might tell you something about.
我知道好几种浪费，上士
I know several kinds of waste, sergeant.
你可能不知道其中一些
You're probably not aware of some of them.
你有兴趣听听吗？
Would you like to hear?
比如家里没有孩子？ 也可以算是一种
For instance, the house without a child? There's one sort for you.
还有另外一种
Then there's another.
你干得好，上士
You're doing fine, sergeant.
我丈夫在休假，外头下着两 而我们两个都在喝酒
My husband's off, it's raining and we're both drinking.
或许你只误判了一件事 那就是夫人我
You probably only got one thing wrong. The lady herself.
或许我并不像外表那样
The lady's not what she seems.
如果你明白我的意思 她过气了
She's a washout, if you know what I mean.
我相信你明白我的意思
And I'm sure you know what I mean.
你想哭吗？
You gonna cry?
我一定忍住不哭
Not if I can help it.
你在做什么？
What are you doing?
我要走了 那不是你所希望的吗？
I'm leaving. Isn't that what you want?
我不知道，上士 我不知道
I don't know, sergeant. I don't know.
快一点  我是很快！发薪日…
Speed it up.   I am. Payday, payday.
够了，马吉欧 你想领钱吗？别闹了
All right, Maggio. You want to get paid? Knock it off.
对不起！我已经赢了不少钱 而且你们赌注太少
Sorry, I already won my bankroll. Besides, it's a penny ante game.
快点！小子！我们要进城去
Come on, buddy boy, we're going to town.
别让他们惹恼你
Don't let them get your goat.
我们可以穿便服 看起来跟别人一样帅
We'll dress in civvies and we're as good as everybody else.
来！穿这件
Here, wear this.
是我姐姐寄来的 她买的东西都太大了些
My sister sent it to me. She buys everything too big.
我们先去几家酒吧逛逛
First we hit a few bars.
我是新国会俱乐部的会员
I'm a member of The New Congress Club.
女孩们！你对女人有偏见吗？
Girls! You got any prejudices against girls?
我也是这么想的
That's what I thought.
你已经为今晚准备整齐了 你想找个伴吗？
You're primed for a big night. You want some company?
不用了！谢谢！我都约好了
No, thanks. All tied up.
列瓦说你在觊觎上尉的老婆
Leva says you've been eyeing the captain's wife.
他这么说吗？ 他还告诉你什么？
He does, huh? What else he tell you?
她在布里斯堡跟过很多男人
She was with a lot of men at Fort Bliss.
我对那些故事没信心
I wouldn't put stock in those stories.
这可不是故事 因为我也是其中之一
This ain't no story. Because I was one of them myself.
只是为期不长 她真的有点奇怪
Not for long, though. Sure is something strange about her.
谢谢你的提醒  回头见
Thanks for the tip.   See you.
你好
Hello.
我没想到你会来  为什么不？我并没有迟到
I didn't think you were coming.   Why not? I ain't late.
没有，但是我早到了 我一定是太过焦虑了
No, but then I got here early. I must have been overanxious.
但是你没有  我先去喝了几杯
You weren't, though.   I stopped for some drinks.
好美的地点 五分钟内就有三个人来约我
A lovely spot. I've had three chances to be picked up in five minutes.
对这样来说是差不多
That's par for the course here.
我不在意 我从不曾有过秘密恋情
I don't care for it. I never went in for back alley loving.
放轻松
Take it easy.
你一定认为我是水性杨花
You must think I'm a tramp.
你为什么认为我会那样想？
What makes you think I'd think that?
用不着这么客气，上士 如果这是个错误，直说无妨
Don't try to be gallant, sergeant. If this is a mistake, say so.
我想我该回家了，不是吗？
I guess it's time for me to go home, isn't it?
不是吗？  是什么让这一切开始的？
Isn't it?   What started all this anyway?
如果这是个错误 我还会来吗？
Would I be here if it was a mistake?
冒了在李汶渥斯待二十年之险 只为了陪伴连长夫人？
Twenty years in Leavenworth for being with the company commander's wife?
而她的态度像亚斯特夫人的马 只因为我准时到达
Her acting like Lady Astor's horse, because I'm on time!
我在衣服里穿了游泳衣
Well, I've got a bathing suit under my dress.
我也一样
Me too.
新国会俱乐部
这不是安杰罗马吉欧吗？  你好！奇佛太太
Why, it's Angelo Maggio.   Greetings, Mrs. Kipfer.
你来了！甜小子 钱都付清了
There you are, sweetie pie. Dues all paid up.
是谁在弹琴？河马吗？
Who's playing the piano, a hippo?
我没见过你的朋友  罗勃普威特大兵
I haven't met your friend.   Private Robert E. Lee Prewitt.
我讨厌你这个样子
I hate it when you're in this condition.
女人看见一位士兵 而且她认为他喝醉了
A woman sees a soldier and she figures he's drunk.
为什么？你知道为什么吗？  因为他是喝醉的
Why? You know why?   Because he is.
喝酒不能跟娱乐业混为一谈
Drinking doesn't mix with the entertainment business.
我们得考虑我们的未来  跟我们一起，你的未来很安全
We have to consider our future.   Your future will be safe with us.
安杰罗是我最爱的客人之一
Angelo is one of my favorites.
阿妮特，请替我招呼这位客人
Annette, take care of this gentleman for me, please.
一共四块钱，娃娃脸
That'll be four bucks, babyface.
两块钱入会费，两块钱月费
Two for initiation, two for this month's dues.
我能得到什么？  俱乐部所有特殊待遇
What do I get?   All the privileges of the club.
跳舞，饮料吧…
Dancing, soft drink bar...
还有与异性风雅的消遗
...and gentlemanly relaxation with the opposite gender.
不可以喝酒，明白了吗？  明白了
No liquor is permitted. Got it?   Got it.
女孩们！又来了新毒药 这是比利珍和南西
Girls, here's some new poison. Billie Jean and Nancy.
很高兴认识你  你好
Nice meeting you.   Hi.
别告诉我，你喜欢公主那种型
Don't tell me the princess is your style.
这两位是苏珊和萝珊
This is Suzanne and Roxanne.
你好  你想跳舞吗？甜心
Hello there.   Would you like to dance, honey?
很感谢你的陪伴 但可否容我失陪？
Much as I adore your company, may I tear myself away?
我看到门口有朋友 看来你已经用不着我了
I saw some friends at the door. And I see I'll be of no more use to you.
嗨！你忙吗？
Hi. You busy?
你叫什么名字？  我叫萝琳
What's your name?   I'm Lorene.
萝琳是吗？
Lorene, huh?
我以前不曾见过你  我没有来过这里
I haven't seen you before.   I haven't been before.
是我朋友带我来的 我们驻扎在雪菲德
My friend brought me. We're stationed at Schofield.
我没想到你是军人  这是什么意思？
I didn't think you were a soldier.   What do you mean?
我今年三十岁 我可是全心奉献
I'm a 30 year man. I'm in for the whole ride.
当男人把它当成事业时 就完全不一样
It's different when a fellow's making a career of it.
当兵并没有什么不对  我还是一样喜欢你
Nothing wrong with a soldier.   I like you just the same.
我一看到你就喜欢你  是吗？
I liked you the minute I saw you.   You did?
真好玩！当我进来时 看到你坐在这里
It's funny. I came in and saw you sitting here.
停下来或者用个消音器  我想弹多大声都行！意大利佬
Knock it off or put a mute in it.   I'll play as loud as I want, wop!
意大利佬？
Wop?!
我要修理你，胖子  你急着找大麻烦，意大利佬
I'll bust you up, fat stuff.   You're in a hurry for trouble, wop.
在这里等我  没问题
Wait right here for me.   Yeah, sure.
墨索里尼在教我弹琴  你弄伤了我的耳膜
Mussolini's telling me how to play!   You're busting my ear drums!
拜托  别打了
Please.   Break it up.
如果你不能守规矩就得离开  只有朋友能叫我“意大利佬”
You must go if you can't behave.   Only my friends call me "wop"!
知道他是谁吗？  我不在乎
Know who he is?   I don't care.
胖子贾德森 禁闭室的警卫士官长
Fatso Judson, sergeant of the guard at the stockade.
我看过他差点杀了人 他乐在其中
I seen him nearly murder a guy. He likes it.
你赢了战争！我们跳舞吧  我得先镇静一下
You won the war, let's dance.   First I got to calm my nerves.
我们到电话亭去
Let's go to a phone booth.
我要把藏在夏威夷衫下的 一大瓶威士忌喝掉
I'll unveil a fifth of whiskey I have hidden under my sportshirt.
别受伤了，朋友
Don't get hurt, pal.
你一定要有无讹的平衡感
Your balance has got to be letter perfect.
我以为你在等  比尔正在说冲浪的事
You were gonna wait.   Bill was talking about surfboarding.
坐下来听！他讲得很刺激
Sit and listen. He describes it thrillingly.
你知道冲浪吗？  完全不了解
You know about surfboarding?   Not a thing.
我住在迪罗西所以有很多机会
I'm at DeRussey, so I get lots of chances.
但是我们有山
But we got mountains.
你知道如何爬山吗？  一点点
Do you know mountain climbing?   A bit.
你很会爬山吗？  不会！你会开飞机吗？
You a mountain climber?   No. Know how to fly an airplane?
我上过几堂课  我也不会开飞机
I had a few lessons.   I can't fly either.
你对于深海潜水了解多少吗？
What do you know about deep sea diving?
我们去别的房间
Let's go to another room.
空气好像变得很混浊  我也注意到了
The air seems to have gotten lousy.   I noticed that.
听着！老兄  走吧！我们走
Listen, fella.   Come on, let's go.
深海潜水夫怎么了？  你的态度糟透了
How's the deep sea diver?   That was a terrible way you acted.
或许我只是嫉妒  你真的很好玩
Maybe I was jealous.   You're a funny one.
你们女人到底想怎样？ 玩弄男人到死吗？
What do you dames want? To tease a man to death?
奇佛太太付钱请我们 对所有男人好
Mrs. Kipfer pays us to be nice to all the boys.
他们都一样，这很重要吗？
They're all alike. Is it so important?
是很重要 或许我们很相像但我们并不一样
It is important. We may seem alike, but we ain't.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我们到奇佛太太的接待室坐一下
Look, let's go to Mrs. Kipfer's parlor and sit there.
她让我们用来接待特别贵宾
She lets us use it for somebody special.
我去问她
I'll go ask her.
你不生气了？  不气了
Then you're not mad?   No.
如果你生气了 我宁可不再继续
Because if you are, I'd rather we call the whole thing off.
你真的是个好玩的家伙
You certainly are a funny one.
我从来不知道是这样子的 没有人像你这样吻过我
I never knew it could be like this. Nobody ever kissed me the way you do.
没有人？  没有
Nobody?   No. Nobody.
一个都没有？ 你所吻过的所有男人？
Not even one? Out of all the men you've been kissed by?
那可得好好算算
That'd take some figuring.
你想有多少人？  我不知道
How many do you think?   I don't know.
告诉我一个估计  没有计算机算不出来
Give me an estimate.   Not without an adding machine.
你有计算机吗？  我忘了带
Do you have one?   I forgot to bring it.
那么我想你是不会知道
Then I guess you won't find out.
或许我已经知道了
Maybe I already know.
怎么了？你在暗示什么？
What's the matter? What are you hinting at?
有什么好暗示的吗？
Is there something to hint at?
搞不好有过很多海滩派对  你一定是疯了
Maybe there were many beach parties.   You must be crazy.
是吗？你跟荷姆斯 在布里斯堡又如何？
Am I? What about when you and Holmes were at Fort Bliss?
你听说过史塔克大兵吗？ 梅隆史塔克？
Did you ever hear of a soldier named Stark? Maylon Stark?
是知道的  “是知道的”
Why, yes.   "Why, yes."
你也认识他，对吧？对吧！
You knew him too, didn't you? Didn't you!
你跟其他人都一样
You're like all the rest of them.
那些事都是真的，对吧？ 对不对？
Only it's true, ain't it? Well, ain't it?
你为什么不告诉我？ 总是有故事的
Why don't you tell me about it? There's always a story.
你不留给任何人任何余地 对吧？
You don't leave a person anything, do you?
回来！上士 我会把故事告诉你
Come back here, sergeant. I'll tell you the story.
你可以把故事带回营区
You can take it back to the barracks with you.
我只结婚了两年 就发现他有外遇
I'd only been married two years when I found out he was cheating.
当时我已经怀孕 让我有了可以期待的事
By that time, I was pregnant. I had something to hope for.
阵痛开始那晚 我差点觉得高兴
I was almost happy the night the pains began.
唐纳去出席军官会议
Dana was going to an officers' conference.
我告诉他要早点带医生回来
I told him to get home early, with a doctor.
那会议不是和女人开的话 他就会照办
And he would have, if his conference hadn't been with a girl.
他到了凌晨五点才喝醉了回来 当时我躺在地板上
He came in at 5 a.m., drunk. I was lying on the floor.
我求他去找医生 可是他醉倒在沙发上
I begged him to go for the doctor, but he passed out on the couch.
孩子在一小时后生了下来 当然是死了
The baby was born about an hour later. Of course it was dead.
是一个男孩 他们送我到医院急救
A boy. They worked over me at the hospital.
他们救活了我 还免费替我割了盲肠
They fixed me up. They took my appendix out, for free.
凯伦？  还有一件事，我也不能生育了
Karen?   And one more thing: No more children.
我是跟男人出游 看看我能否找到一个…
Sure, I went out with men. And if I'd found one that...
凯伦，听我说
Karen, listen to me, listen.
我知道！直到我遇见你 我也认为这是不可能的
I know. Until I met you, I didn't think it was possible either.
我也到军中服务 独自一人离开奥勒冈的家
I enlisted too. I came on my own to get away from my hometown in Oregon.
怎么会？
How come?
我原本是个女侍 我男友来自最富裕的家庭
I was a waitress. My boyfriend was from the richest family.
他娶了一个符合地位的女孩
He married a girl suitable for his position...
当时他已与我交往了三年 很棒的故事吧？
...after three years of going with me. It's a pretty story, isn't it?
这个故事可以写一本书  写过了！太多人写了
They could write a book about it.   They did. Thousands of 'em.
所以我离家到了西雅图 我遇见一个从夏威夷回去的女孩
I left and went to Seattle. I met a girl back from Hawaii.
她在那里赚了大钱 所以我搭上第一班船
She'd made money there. So I caught the first boat.
我已经来这里一年两个月  而你并不喜欢
I've been here a year and two months.   You don't like it.
我是不喜欢但我并不在意 我不会永远待在这里
I don't like it. But I don't mind it. I won't be here forever.
当然不会，为什么要呢？
No. Sure. I mean, why should you?
再过一年我就会赚了很多钱 回家去了
In another year, I'll be back home, with a stocking full of money.
之后我可以重新过生活
And then I'll be all set for life.
哪一位？
Who is it?
我没有听到争吵声 所以以为你们也想喝一杯
I didn't hear no combat, so I thought you might want a drink.
你独占那瓶威士忌，安杰罗
You've been hogging the whiskey, Angelo.
不是我！是珊卓拉 她是很好可是太会喝酒了
Not me. It's that Sandra. She's nice, but she drinks like a fish.
我希望下面有警察
I hope there's a cop under that.
继续倒
Keep pouring.
不了！谢谢！我不喝酒 我觉得那是个缺点
No, thanks. I don't drink. I think it's a weakness.
我允许你的看法
I grant you that.
我不喜欢缺点，你呢？
I don't like weakness. Do you?
不喜欢，但我想喝酒
No, but I like to drink.
你要嫁给这家伙吗？ 你对他笑的样子好像是他老婆
You gonna marry this guy? You grin at him like you're his wife.
滚出去！
Get out of here!
好…我要回去找长腿珊卓拉
Okay. Okay. I'm going. Back to long legged Sandra.
我喜欢腿长！绵延不绝
I love them tall. Acres and acres.
好好享受！老兄 你比我更需要这个
Enjoy yourself, paisan. You need this more than I do.
明天你得继续接受特训
Tomorrow you're back with the Treatment.
他是什么意思？
What does he mean?
你在他面前依偎在我身边真好
That was nice how you snuggled up in front of him.
什么是特训？
What's a Treatment?
有些人因为我不打拳 所以对我施压
Some guys putting me over the jumps because I don't want to fight.
打拳？  是的，参加拳击队
Fight?   Yeah. On the boxing team.
我不想打拳击
I don't want to box.
你为什么一定要打拳呢？
Why should you have to box?
我以前是打中量级的
I used to fight, middleweight.
而且我打得很好 他们大家都知道
I was pretty good, and they know it.
快点告诉我！我想听
Come on. Tell me. I want to hear.
当时我跟一个叫 迪西威尔斯的人练习
Well, I used to work out with this guy, Dixie Wells.
他是我的一位好朋友 他很喜欢拳击
He's a real good friend of mine. He loved to box.
外头的人都看好他
People on the outside had their eye on him.
他原本可以晋到最高级
He was gonna go right to the top.
有天下午 我跟他在健身房练习对打
One afternoon, he and I were sparring in the gym.
你知道，就是友善那种打法
You know, kind of friendly like.
他可能是太累了
And he must have been set pretty flat on his feet...
因为我不过是…
...because I caught him with...
用普通力气打了他一记右拳
...a no more than an ordinary right cross.
他没有爬起来，动也不动 他昏迷了一个礼拜
He didn't get up. He didn't move. He was in a coma for a week.
最后终于清醒了
And finally did pull out of it.
可是他却瞎了
The thing was that he was blind.
我到医院去看了他几次
I went to see him at the hospital a couple of times.
后来我再也无法去看他
Then, I just couldn't go back.
最后一次当我们谈起拳击
The last time we started talking about fighting and...
他开始哭
...he started to cry.
看着那双瞎了的眼睛流着泪…
And seeing tears coming out of those eyes that couldn't see anything...
我应该告诉你 荷姆斯跟他的拳手谈过了
I ought to tell you. Holmes spoke to his boxers.
从现在开始，不会对你客气
From now on, no holds barred.
他们打算将你逼进禁闭室  任由他们
They aim to run you in the stockade.   Let them.
我会帮你 可是我不能太过明显
I'll help you, but I can't get too far out on a limb.
我不会牺牲自己的军阶 我喜欢这个军团
I ain't risking my stripes. I like this outfit.
我也一样
So do I.
真好笑，不是吗？  是的，是很好笑
That's funny, ain't it?   Yeah, that is funny.
保持一直线，普威特
Keep going in a straight line, Prewitt.
继续走！
Keep going!
好了！够了
All right, that's enough.
普威特！把它埋了
Okay, Prewitt, bury it.
时间到
Time!
把这里清干净，普威特
Clean up the mess, Prewitt.
快！这是劳动！可不是在度假
Hurry up! You're on fatigue detail, not a vacation.
快点！把它清干净
Come on! Clean it up!
你自己清
Clean it up yourself!
什么？  要清你自己去清理
What?   Rub your own nose in it a while.
你不该跟无委任状士官顶嘴
You shouldn't talk back to a noncommissioned officer.
但我可不喜欢 被无委任士官侮辱
But I don't like being spit on by a noncommissioned officer.
你应该向他道歉  绝不，长官
You owe him an apology.   No, sir.
是他该向我道歉
He owes me an apology.
帕路索下士  是的，长官
Corporal Peluso?   Yes, sir.
让这个人全副武装 带他去跑可洛可洛山路
Have this man roll a full field pack and hike him up to Kolekole Pass.
然后再带他来见我  是的，长官
And then bring him to me.   Yes, sir.
好了，普威特！我们走  时间
All right, Prewitt, let's go.   Time!
等一下
Hold it a minute.
抽根烟吧 我跟你一样不喜欢这种事
Go ahead, have a cigarette. I don't like this any more than you.
你预备好向 葛罗维奇士官道歉？
You're ready to apologize to Sergeant Galovitch now?
不，长官！我不道歉
No, sir, I'm not.
帕路索！再带他去跑一圈  是的，长官
Peluso, take him up there again.   Yes, sir.
好了，普威特！我们走
All right, Prewitt, let's go.
你不能善待这种人 他好像是头野兽似的
You can't be decent to a man like that! He's like an animal.
上士，准备军法审判的表格 罪名是抗命
Sergeant, prepare court martial papers. Insubordination.
是的，长官
Yes, sir.
只是太可惜了  怎么了？
Only it's a shame.   What is?
你将会失去一名中量级好手
You'll lose a good middleweight.
我不需要忍受他的无礼
I don't have to stand for insolence!
不，长官！当然用不着
No, sir, you sure don't.
我马上准备表格
I'll prepare the papers then.
就算他只被判刑三个月 决赛时他会待在禁闭室中
Even if he gets three months, he'll still be in stockade for the finals.
你有办法说服他吗？
Do you see any other way of breaking him?
你可以加重惩罚，长官
You could double punishment, sir.
我会用重刑  如果你那么觉得的话，长官
I'll throw the book at him.   Lf you think that's the way, sir.
好建议！上士
Nice going, sarge.
继续看的话 你会发现自己在刷地板
Keep looking, you'll find yourself scrubbing this floor!
借过！
Coming through!
我和服务生们已经忙坏了 烫！烫！
Me and my waiters are working our tails off. Hot! Hot!
你好吗？在这里比被关禁闭好
How you doing? It's better than being in the stockade.
我好吗？我是个粗人
How am I doing? I'm a rough man.
慢一点！汗别滴到菜上
Slow down. Don't sweat in the food.
不要阻止我 我正在申请升下士
Don't hold me back. I'm putting in for corporal.
你成功不了的
You'll never make it.
一生都得待在步兵团里
Life in a rifle company.
你看起来很累的样子，小子
You look awful tired, kid.
你喜欢连续当班吗？
How do you like straight duty?
你认为我会介意吗？  我没有那么说
You think I mind it?   I didn't say that.
我只是说你看来很累的样子 好像快崩溃似的
I just said you looked tired. Drawn to a fine edge.
我喜欢这种生活！棒极了
I like this life. It's great.
如果我找到珍珠，我会算你一份 跟你平分，知道吗？
If I find a pearl, I'll cut you in. 50 50, you know?
如果不是你让我来这里 我不会有机会去找它
If you didn't put me here, I'd have no chance to find it.
你真是的
There's a man for you.
既然你喜欢 我会再多替你找一些
Since you like it, I'll find more for you.
垃圾小队怎么样？  谢了！礼拜三已经做过了
How about garbage detail?   Thanks, I had that on Wednesday.
原来做过了 那么扫街如何？
So you did. What about street cleaning?
昨天扫过了  你的记忆力比我的更好
Yesterday.   You got a better memory than me.
当然！如果你聪明的话…  说得是！但我并不聪明
Of course, if you were smart...   Yeah, but I ain't smart.
但如果你聪明 你就用不着做炊事兵
But if you were, you wouldn't have to pull K.P.
或者其他劳动工作
Or any other fatigue duty for that matter.
如果你认为可以说服我打拳 那你就错了
If you think you can bribe me into boxing, you're wrong.
你错了！你没有办法 荷姆斯跟特训也办不到
You're wrong. Not you and Dynamite Holmes and the Treatment.
你还要压迫普威特多久？
How long will you keep breaking it off on Prewitt?
你已连续一个月罚他加班了 我不明白为什么你…
You've had him on extra duty for a month. I can't see why you...
年纪大心也变软了吗？ 或许我是在给他些教训
Getting soft in your old age? Maybe I'm teaching him a lesson.
或许是你喜欢这样  或许我是喜欢
Maybe you like it.   Maybe I do.
我不想再看你做荷姆斯的爪牙
I'm getting tired of watching you being a stooge for Holmes.
你不会再看多久了
You won't see it much longer.
我自己也很厌烦 我随时都可以不干！真的
I'm tired of it myself. I'm through, any day now. I mean it!
只要荷姆斯允许 我宁可明天就请调
If Holmes'd let me, I'd transfer out tomorrow.
有半打以上的军团会争取我 而且还会有官阶
Half a dozen companies would grab me. In grade too.
当然！我还可以做参谋长
Sure. I could be chief of staff too.
但我不能离开我的弟兄  你要上哪儿去？应声虫
Only I just can't leave my buddies.   Where you going, Little Sir Echo?
去冲澡！除非士官长反对
To shower, unless the stinking first sergeant objects.
你以为了呢？去看电影吗？  快点！我们去喝几杯啤酒
What'd you think? To the movies?   Hurry up. We'll get some beer.
就算那是世上最后的啤酒也不去
Not if it was the last beer in the world.
我请客
I'm buying.
那就不一样了
That's different.
萝丝
Rose.
知道为何我喜欢你为我服务？ 这样我才能看着你走开
Know why I like to have you serve me? So I can watch you walk away.
你有权抱怨 你可以去向督察长申诉
You got a right to complain, to take it to the inspector general.
任何士兵都可以 就连普通二等兵都行
Any soldier has, even a plain dogface.
不！我不会去申诉
Nope. I ain't going to complain.
我不会让他们得到满足的
They ain't going to get that satisfaction.
我有一大家人，一共十五人 这里只有一半而已
I've got a real big family, 15 of them. This is only half.
你看到那个留八字胡的先生？
You see the gentleman with the handlebars?
那是我父亲，马吉欧先生
That's Mr. Maggio, my father.
从没见过如此顽固的人 离他们上次让你进城有多久了？
Never saw anybody so stubborn. How long since they let you go to town?
六个星期  搞不好会六年
Six weeks.   It's liable to be six years.
六年你都看不到女人  你何不管好自己的事？
Six years before you see a dame.   Why don't you mind your own business?
你为什么不去学吹号角？
And why don't you learn to play the bugle?
那才是我的好兄弟
That's my buddy boy!
这小妞是谁？  是我姐姐
Who's the broad?   It's my sister.
你打我  没错！而且我会再打
You hit me!   Yeah, and I'm about to do it again.
你这个肮脏的意大利佬
Why, you dirty wop!
到外面解决  我要切下这义佬的心脏
Take it outside!   I'll cut this wop's heart out.
如果有人敢插手 我会先修理他
Anybody steps in here, I'll give it to him first.
再往前一步，胖子 我就会砍了你的脑袋
One step further, Fatso, and I'll de brain you.
这里只有我才可以杀人
Anybody does any killing here, I'll do it!
这是私事  不！他属于我的军团
This is a private affair.   No, it ain't! He's in my company.
不要无缘无故的替我制造麻烦
You ain't making two extra weeks of paperwork for me.
非打不可吗？ 搞不好会把胆汁都吐出来
Out for blood? You'd puke your guts out.
把凳子放下
Put down that stool.
把它放下
Put it down!
把刀子扔掉
Drop that knife.
好吧！胖子！ 如果你想杀人就来吧！
Okay, Fatso, if it's killing you want, come on.
来吧！
Well, come on.
丢到地板上
On the floor!
杀手？我宁可用你们 来交换一个女童军
Killers, huh? I'd trade the pair of you for a good Campfire Girl!
泼猴
Tough monkey.
你这种人迟早会被关禁闭
Guys like you end up in the stockade sooner or later.
总有一天我会等着你被关进来
Someday you'll walk in, I'll be waiting.
到时我会要你好看
I'll show you a couple of things.
我要出去呼吸点空气
I'm going to get a breath of air.
我很高兴他阻止了这件事
I'm glad he stopped it.
他是个好人
A good man.
你留着！留做纪念
You keep it. Keep it for a souvenir.
好吧！我会留着
Okay, I'll keep it.
你不太有机会享受生活吧？小子
You ain't enjoying life much, are you, kid?
你周末想放假吗？  可以吗？
Could you stand a weekend pass?   Could I?
荷姆斯怎么办？
What about Holmes?
别担心！我放在他面前的文件 他都会签字
Don't worry. He signs anything I put in front of him.
我会用的到的
I sure could use it.
听说你迷恋上 新国会俱乐部一位小姐
I hear you're dippy over a dame at the New Congress Club.
她叫什么名字？  萝琳
What'd you say her name was?   Lorene.
好美的名字
Beautiful name.
嗨！老兄
Hey, paisan!
是什么绊住你了？我们走
What's holding you up? Let's go.
怎么了？你不喜欢这里吗？
What's the matter? Don't you like it here?
巴士就快开了！我要赶去搭车
The bus is leaving now. I'm taking it.
快走！我是有钱人 我会搭计程车
Take off. I'm a rich man. I'll hop a taxi.
我到卡拉库瓦跟你碰面
I'll meet you at the Kalakaua later.
马吉欧！预备上哨
Maggio, get ready for guard!
戴宽边毯帐，子弹腰带 武器！十分钟内报到
Campaign hat, cartridge belt, weapon! Report in 10 minutes.
什么？我有假单
What?! I got a pass!
那不算！安德生病了 所以你得上哨
Not anymore. Anderson's sick. You're on guard.
我昨天上过哨，为什么是我？
I just had guard yesterday. Why me?
我告诉你原因 你换衣服速度应该快一点
I'll tell you why. You should've gotten dressed faster.
你在回避我吗？ 他们甚至不让我进来
You giving me the runaround? They didn't even want to let me in.
这里有一大群希坎军营来的人 你到底想怎么样？
A big crowd from Hickam Field is here. Anyway, what'd you expect?
我以为你会想见我  我正在忙，看到了吗？
I thought you'd want to see me.   I'm busy, see?
是的，我看到了  我是在忙
Yes, I can see.   Well, I am.
马吉欧待会儿会去卡拉库瓦
Look, Maggio will be at the Kalakaua later.
难道你不能想办法离开吗？
Ain't there no way you can get out of here?
你到底怎么搞的？ 我在这里工作，你不懂吗？
What's the matter with you? I work here. Can't you understand?
是的，我当然明白
Yes, I do understand.
我非常明白
I understand very well.
你几个礼拜都没有来 现在突然出现…
You haven't been around here in weeks, and now you turn up all of a sudden...
小心！老兄！走路要看路
Watch it, mac! Watch where you're going!
我们到外面去
Come on out of here.
奇佛太太有规定 我不能这样就走掉了
Mrs. Kipfer has rules. I can't just walk out.
我们不能在外面跟男孩约会
We can't see the boys on the outside.
如果你是这种感觉那就算了
If you feel that way, just forget about it.
你管不着我 你又不是我丈夫
You haven't any claims on me. You're not my husband.
原来你在这里，萝琳 我欣赏你的品味但我们需要她
There you are, Lorene. I admire your taste, dear, but we need her now.
有许多位先生没有人陪伴 真是忙坏了
So many of the gentlemen are unattended. It is such a rush.
搞不好有人会误解 我们在开大型政治会议
One might almost mistake us for a big political convention.
你来吧？萝琳  马上来
You are coming, Lorene?   In a minute.
对不起
I'm sorry.
你认为我有什么感觉？ 搞不好我几个月都无法拿到假条
How do you think I feel? I may not get another pass for months.
我期待这次见面 就像小孩期待耶诞节一样
I been counting on this like a kid counts on Christmas.
还是算了吧！萝琳在忙 萝琳很抱歉
But forget it. Lorene's busy. Lorene's sorry.
别再叫我萝琳 我的本名叫艾玛
Stop calling me Lorene! My name's Alma!
艾玛？  是的，艾玛伯克
Alma?   Yes, Alma Burke!
艾玛？
Alma?
奇佛太太从香水广告上 挑了萝琳这个名字
Mrs. Kipfer picked "Lorene" out of a perfume ad.
她觉得这个名字很有法国风味
She thought it sounded French.
你怎么脱身的？
How did you get away?
我说我病了 但我打赌她并不相信
I said I was sick. But I bet she doesn't believe it.
我赌她不信  你想喝什么？
I bet she doesn't.   What'll you have?
可乐，谢谢  给她可乐，大可乐
A Coke, please.   Give her a Coke, big Coke.
你能来这里见我真好
It's great you meeting me here.
我是运气好才能进城 军士长饶了我
I'm lucky to get to town. Topkick gave me a break.
他们还在施压吗？
They still pouring it on?
他们真的让我快要崩溃  你一定很恨军队
They really got me on the edge.   Gee, you must hate the Army.
不，我不恨它  但把你折磨成这样
No, I don't hate it.   But look what it's doing to you.
我爱军队
I love the Army.
但它一定不爱你
But it sure doesn't love you.
男人爱一样东西 并不表示一定有所回报
A man loves a thing, that don't mean it's got to love him back.
没错，但人的忍耐有限
Yeah, but a person can stand just so much.
你爱某件事，你应该感恩
You love a thing, you gotta be grateful.
我在十七岁时离家 我的父母亲都死了
See, I left home when I was 17. Both my folks is dead.
我没有归属感直到入伍为止
And I didn't belong no place till I entered the Army.
而且我还学会吹号角
And I wouldn't have learned how to bugle.
吹号角？
To bugle?
这个吹口就是我在 阿灵顿公墓吹丧葬号时用的
That's the mouthpiece I used when I played a taps at Arlington.
他们选我在休战纪念日 吹奏丧葬号角
They picked me to play a taps there on Armistice Day.
总统也到场
The president was there.
我的号角吹得很好
I play the bugle well.
嗨！老百姓
Hello, citizens!
你上哪儿去了？
Hey, where you been?
我已经去过三家酒吧 我对三家酒吧都做了些奉献
I've been in three bars and I put a dent in all three.
没错！看来就像
Yeah, you look it.
给我些酒  你怎么会穿制服？
Give me a nail.   What you doing in uniform?
我正考虑从军
I'm thinking of joining the Army.
或许我该到墨西哥当牛仔 你愿意跟我一起去吗？
Or maybe I'll go to Mexico and become a cowboy. You want to go with me?
你再继续喝酒 就会像溶掉的蜡烛一样游泳
You keep drinking, you'll be as much use as a melted candle.
你说得很对 酒保！威士忌！大杯的
You're absolutely right. Bartender, whiskey! Large whiskey.
借过，老兄
Excuse me. Hey, buddy.
山姆
Sam!
各位！金贝地下室的怪物 就要出笼了
Coming out, fellas, the terror of Gimbel's basement.
让开！出个七点 五点，两点
Stand back now. A seven for Daddy. Five, deuce.
七点
A seven.
两个么点 那正是我一生的高潮
Snake eyes. That's the story of my life.
夏威夷皇家饭店就在附近
That's the Royal Hawaiian around the corner.
电影明星常在那里出现
Where all those movie stars stay.
你最好安静下来 你还有整个周末要过
You better simmer down. You got a whole weekend ahead of you.
那是你说的，兄弟
That's what you say, buddy.
他们只给你过夜假条吗？  没有假条
They only gave you an overnight pass?   No pass.
他们让我上哨 可是老安杰罗骗过他们了
They put me on guard duty. But old Angelo, he foxed them.
你擅离岗哨？
You walked off guard?
我签到之后立刻签出
I checked in and checked right out.
你赶快回到岗哨去 你的麻烦大了
You get your tail back to the post. You're in trouble.
我有个好主意 我们去跟电影明星游泳
I got a good idea. Let's go swimming with a movie star.
我正打算那么做 去跟电影明星游泳
That's what I'll do, go swimming with a movie star!
二十英尺高 我要去跟电影明星游泳
Twenty feet tall. I'm swimming with a movie star.
你最好快走吧！
You better go.
混球！快走来！醒醒
You jerk, get up. Wake up!
我是清醒的！你干嘛大吼？
I'm awake. Why are you hollering?
把衣服穿上
Put your clothes on.
把它们送给印第安人 他们会需要的
Give them back to the Indians. They need them.
他们只穿丁字裤
All they wear is G strings.
你没有喝醉！快起来
You ain't drunk. Get up.
我要在这里等电影明星 从饭店里出来
I am waiting here for a movie star to come out of the hotel...
除非她出现否则我不会走
...and I'm not going until she shows up.
把衣服穿上
Put your clothes on.
在我们惹上麻烦之前赶快离开
Let's get out of here before we get in trouble.
你是怎么回事？ 难道我不能喝醉吗？
What's the matter with you? Can't a man get drunk?
难道我不能做自己想做的事？
Can't a man do nothing?
难道我不能手插在口袋里 走在大街上吗？
Can't he put his lousy hands in his lousy pockets on a lousy street?
难道我必须一生被追逐吗？
A man got to be hounded all his life?
我累了！我又不是罪犯
Well, I'm tired. I ain't no criminal.
我也不是懦夫  兄弟，你瞧
I ain't no coward!   Buddy boy, look.
你把衣服穿好 快把衣服穿上
You get dressed. You put your clothes on.
等我！我去叫计程车  是才怪
Wait for me, I'll get a cab.   Yeah, sure.
你会等吧？  是的，你去叫计程车
Will you wait?   Yeah, you get a cab.
嗨！宪兵
Hey, MPs!
你们快来抓我！我在这里
Come and get me, you guys! Here I am!
你们只能这样吗？ 我想你们一定是吃脆麦片的
Is that the best you can do? I bet you guys eat Wheaties!
军事法庭有消息吗？
Any word on the court martial?
现在正在审
It's on right now.
他一定会被关禁闭
He'll get the stockade sure.
或许他不会被关 他只不过是喝醉了
Maybe he won't get it. All he did was to get drunk.
那是军人的本色 偶尔变成义务了
It's a soldier's nature, almost a duty once in a while.
可是他擅离职守
But he went AWOL.
你为什么在这里？  男子汉不能休息吗？
Why are you here?   Can't a man rest?
什么男子汉？你没事做吗？ 我可以派一些给你
What man? You got no work? Maybe I can scare you up some.
去打几杆撞球 有任何消息我会通知你
Go shoot some pool. Any word comes, I'll let you know.
参谋本部，华登上士 是的，长官
Company G, First Sergeant Warden. Yes, sir.
我会把他的东西准备好
I'll have his things in order.
他被判刑了，六个月
He got it. Six months.
金贝的地下室关不了我 禁闭室也一样关不住
Gimbel's basement couldn't hold me, neither can this stockade.
闭嘴！  全听你的，女童军
Shut up!   Whatever you say, Brownie.
囚犯！停
Prisoner, halt!
警卫士官长
你好，泼猴
Hello, tough monkey.
我们很幸运能租到它 这是个迎合潮流的好区
We were lucky to rent it. This is a very fashionable district.
我替你打了钥匙
I had a key made for you.
你随时都可以用它 就算我不在也可以
You can use it any time, even when I'm not here.
普威特就是我跟你提起的大兵 乔琪特，我的室友
Prew is the soldier I told you about. Georgette, my roommate.
欢迎你，朋友
Welcome, friend.
自从那只猫死了以后 屋里就没有男的了
There hasn't been a man around the house since the cat died.
我每次必订阅书会的书
I always take every book from the Book Club.
那是我分得红利的方式
That's the way I get all the dividends.
等马吉欧出禁闭室后 她会很适合他
She'll be great for Maggio when he gets out.
是的，他会为她疯狂
Yes, he'll be crazy about her.
请坐！让自己舒服一下
Just sit down and get comfortable.
我去替你调杯马丁尼 再去准备晚饭
I'll make you a martini and see about dinner.
感觉好像结了婚，对吧？
This is like being married, ain't it?
好比结了婚
It's better.
你还好吗？
You okay?
很高兴你来了吗？
Glad you came?
我们走吧！不要回头
Let's get out of here. Don't look around.
我们不能再这样继续下去
It can't go on like this much longer.
就算是到了岛这一头 我们还是得…
Even clear across the island, we had to...
像囚犯一样逃跑
...run out like jail birds.
如果我们有办法…
If there was only a way we...
荷姆斯会让你离婚 可是他不会让我请调
Holmes'd give you a divorce, but he'd never let me transfer.
是有一个办法
There is a way.
我一直在考虑这件事 你必须去做军官
I've been thinking about it. You've got to become an officer.
就读新的额外课程 然后他们就会送你回美国
Take the new extension course. Then they'll ship you back to the States.
当军官？
An officer?
是的！这样我可以跟 唐纳离婚再嫁给你
Yes. Then I could divorce Dana and marry you.
我讨厌军官 我一直很讨厌军官
I hate officers! I've always hated them!
那可是个很明智的看法
That's a fine, intelligent point of view.
如果我说我讨厌上士呢？ 这样合理多了
If I said I always hated sergeants? That'd make a lot of sense.
你已经研究得很透澈
You sure made a complete study of it.
好吧！假设我是研究过 别以为这事很容易
Okay, suppose I did. And don't think it's a cinch.
我们必须分开六个月 到时我们一定会参战
We'd be apart six months! We're sure to be in a war by then.
老实说吧！你只是不想负责任
Tell the truth. You just don't want the responsibility.
搞不好你根本不爱我
You probably don't love me.
你疯了！真希望我不爱你 或许我可以再次享受人生
You're crazy! I wish I didn't. Maybe I could enjoy life again.
于是他们结了婚 从此过着不快乐的生活
So, they were married and lived unhappily ever after.
在我遇见你之前 我从不曾如此悲惨
I've never been so miserable as I have since I met you.
我也没有
Neither have I.
我不愿再抛弃一分钟
I wouldn't trade a minute of it.
我也不愿意
Neither would I.
或许我会成为 你见过最差的军官
I'll probably make the lousiest officer you ever saw.
你一定会是个好军官
You'll make a fine officer.
一个很棒的军官
A remarkable officer.
谢谢你
Thank you.
过来
Come here.
难道你不能等我们吃完晚餐？
Can't you wait until we finish dinner?
亲爱的  什么事？
Honey.   What?
我想娶你
I want to marry you.
你真是个好玩的家伙
You're a funny one.
为什么有人想娶你 是件好玩的事？
Why is it funny if a guy wants to marry you?
因为你是在 新国会俱乐部认识我
Because you met me at the New Congress Club.
那只不过比最底层高一点而已
That's two steps up from the pavement.
我是什么？不过是个大兵 没有阶级的大兵
Well, what am I? I'm a private, no class dogface.
大部分的人会认为我什么都不是
Most civilians look at that as two steps up from nothing.
我以为我们很快乐 你为何要毁了这一切？
I thought we were happy. Why do you want to spoil things?
听着！我还有一年就要延役
Look, I've got a year to go before I re enlist.
如果到时候我能升为士官 我就可以回美国
If I get sergeant stripes by then, I can go back to the States.
到时我们可以一起回去 如果你愿意等的话
Then we can go back together if you'll wait.
你在荷姆斯手下如何升成士官？
How could you become a sergeant under Holmes?
你只能尽量不被关禁闭
It's all you can do to keep out of the stockade.
我愿意打拳击
I'll fight.
不，你用不着打拳击  那是值得的
No, you won't fight.   It'd be worth it.
现在我们彼此是相爱 我们相互需要
It's true we love each other now, we need each other.
但回到美国，就可能大不相同
But back in the States, it might be different.
那不是真正的理由
That ain't the real reason.
好吧！那不是  什么是真正理由？
All right, it's not.   What is the real reason?
我不想成为士兵的太太
I don't want to be the wife of a soldier.
我最好只能为你做到那样
That would be about the best I could ever do for you.
因为没有人能妨碍我的计划 没有任何人或任何事
Because nobody'll stop me from my plan. Nobody, nothing.
因为我想做高尚人  高尚？
Because I want to be proper.   Proper?
是的，高尚
Yes, proper.
再过一年，我的钱就存够了
In another year, I'll have enough money.
我打算回到奥勒冈 替我妈和自己盖栋房子
Then I'll go back to Oregon and build a house for my mother and myself.
然后加入乡村俱乐部 学打高尔夫球
And join the country club and take up golf.
我会遇到有高尚地位的高尚男士
I'll meet the proper man with the proper position.
我将成为高尚的太太 掌高尚的家，生养高尚的孩子
I'll be a proper wife who can run a proper home and raise proper children.
我会很快乐 因为高尚的人很安全
And I'll be happy because when you're proper, you're safe.
你很有勇气，亲爱的
You got guts, honey.
我希望你能成功
I hope you can pull it off.
当我说需要你时是真心的
I do mean it when I say I need you.
因为我很寂寞
Because I'm lonely.
你认为我在说谎，对吧？
You think I'm lying, don't you?
没有人会用寂寞来说谎话
Nobody ever lies about being lonely.
不要跟我提离婚的事
Don't talk to me about a divorce.
为什么？难道丑闻会 破坏你升迁的机会？
Why? Because the scandal would spoil your chances for a promotion?
我要知道对方是谁 以及你是在哪里认识他的
I want to know who he is and where you met him.
我绝对不会告诉你
I'm not going to tell you.
我知道他是个老百姓 你谨慎的不会找军人
I know he's a civilian. You'd be too discreet to pick an Army man.
我不知道是你的骄傲 还是你的好奇让我重伤？
I wonder which is hurt more, your pride or your curiosity?
你不会知道我的感受
You can't expect to know how I feel.
为什么男人的感觉如此不同？
Why do men feel so differently about it?
根本完全不一样
It's just not the same.
今天天气真好，我想去散个步
It's a lovely day. I think I'll go for a walk.
我听说你才关完禁闭出来
I hear you just got out of the stockade.
那里真的很难捱 我不想再多说
It was rugged. I kept my mouth shut.
你有见到马吉欧吗？  胖子把马吉欧折磨得很惨
Did you see Maggio?   Fatso's really got it in for Maggio.
他甚至用了警棍
He's using a billy, too.
专打看不到的地方 比如说背后或胸前
In places where it won't show. On the back, on the chest.
他甚至有个系统 他还经常踢他
He's got it down to a system. He kicks him a lot too.
你知道马吉欧的反应如何？
You know how Maggio's taking it?
他一直对胖子吐口水
He just keeps spitting in Fatso's eye.
他真有个性，是吗？
Ain't he a hot one?
他是一个好人
He's a good man.
老胖子伤不了他 那个胖子是个聪明人
Old Fatso can't make a dent in him. That Fatso, he's smart.
值星官从来看不到什么的  为什么马吉欧不向值星官报告？
The OD never sees nothing.   Why don't Maggio go to the OD?
我们曾鼓励他去报告但他不肯 他真的很倔强
We tried to get him to, but he won't peep. He's a tough nut.
你认为他能平安吗？
You think he'll be all right?
他可能快崩溃了  这话什么意思？
Maybe he's cracking.   What do you mean?
胖子将他关进洞里，就是 单人牢房后…
After Fatso threw him in the hole... that's solitary...
他开始不停地说他要如何逃跑
...he started talking about how he'll escape.
他说他某个晚上会来找你
He said he'll look you up one of these nights.
你还趴在地上吗？普威特
Still on your knees, Prewitt?
拳击决赛在下个月 十二月十五日
Boxing finals next month. December 15th.
你还有时间帮我们赢得冠军
Still time to help us win the championship.
你是否以加入本军团为荣？
Are you proud to be in this company or not?
我不会再绕过你了  看来你需要点教训
I won't move around you again.   Something tells me you need a lesson.
或许我会亲自教训你
Maybe I'll give it to you myself.
别惹他！他是我小队上的人 如果你打架，麻烦可就大了
Leave him alone, he's in my detail. You'll get in trouble if you fight.
回去工作  别挡路
Get back to work.   Get out of the way!
我很乐意提供推荐信
I'll be glad to give my recommendation.
你有功绩，经验和官阶
You've got service, experience, grade.
你一定会成为好军官  谢谢你，长官
You'll make an excellent officer.   Thank you, sir.
军团里能有你这种人 也是值得让我骄傲的事
A feather in my cap too. A man from my company.
出了什么事？
What's the trouble?
葛罗维奇和普威特 他们在外头打架，长官
They're fighting outside, sir. Galovitch and Prewitt.
葛罗维奇会杀了他，长官
Galovitch's going to murder him, sir.
我会处理
I'll take care of it.
难道你不想看吗？  不想！你也别看！出去
Don't you want to see?   No! Nor you, either! Get out!
为什么普威特不打他的头？  他曾打瞎某个人所以很害怕
Why don't Prew go for his head?   He blinded a guy once, he's scared.
揍他的脸
Hit him in the face!
拜托！葛罗维奇！公平竞赛！  我想怎么打都行
Come on, Galovitch, fight fair!   I'll fight any way I want.
那位军官应该阻止这场架 他叫什么名字？
That officer should stop the fight. What's his name?
荷姆斯上尉，长官
Captain Holmes, sir.
稍息！是谁先动手的？
At ease. What started this?
普威特违抗我给他的命令
Prewitt refused order I gave him.
开始顶嘴并且挑衅 所以我才会教训他
Talked back and started a fight. I taught him a lesson.
你不可以再抗命
You won't disobey any more orders.
长官！这件事不能怪普威特 是葛罗维奇上士起头的
I'm sorry, sir, but Prewitt's not to blame. Sergeant Galovitch started it.
索希尔，这个小队是你带的 到底怎么回事？
Thornhill. You're in charge of this detail. What about it?
他说得对，普威特没有犯错  是葛罗维奇起的头
He's right. Prewitt did nothing.   Galovitch started it.
够了！这事算了 回去做自己的工作
That's all. Let's forget it. Let's get back to our jobs.
好了！回去工作 动作快！解散
All right, back to work. Let's go. Break it up.
如果你认为这样我就会出赛 你就错了
If you think this means I'll fight, you're wrong.
你的伤口最好擦点碘酒
You'd better put some iodine on them cuts.
星期五，你怎么会叫星期五？
Hey, Friday. Why're you called "Friday"?
我也不知道 我是在星期三生的
I don't know. I was born on a Wednesday.
普威特，你要去哪里？
Prewitt, where are you going?
什么意思？我要去裘伊酒吧 再多买罐啤酒
What do you mean? I'm going to Choy's to get me another beer.
别动！
Halt!
谁在那里？
Who goes there?
一个朋友  朋友，请你上前表明身份
A friend.   Advance, friend, and be recognized!
立正！
Ten hut!
向后转！向后转走！
About face! Rear face!
跪下！刷地板
On your knees! Scrub the floor!
稍息
At ease.
小子，你一个人在这做什么？
Hello, kid. What you doing out here all by yourself?
我去买酒  坐下！我还有一瓶
I'm getting a little drink.   Sit down. I got a bottle.
谢谢，军士长
Thanks, top.
我一定得称赞你 揍葛罗维奇的方法，小子
I got to hand it to you, kid, the way you beat up old Galovitch.
可惜他们迟早会扳倒你
Too bad they got to get you sooner or later.
生命就是这么烂，你知道吗？
Life's crummy, you know it?
是的，长官，是很悲惨 非常地悲惨
Yes, sir, it's miserable, perfectly miserable.
如果现在有辆卡车 开过来撞上我们怎么办？
What would happen if a truck came along and ran us over?
我们就死定了  你最好别再坐在这里
We'd be dead.   You better not sit here anymore.
起来坐到路旁去
Get up and sit over on the side.
你在说什么？我…可是…
What do you mean, I? But...
你比我更需要活下去 你还得照顾整个军团
You've got more to live for than me, a whole company to take care of.
你快移到路旁
You move over to the other side.
我年纪比较大，死了没关系
I'm older, it don't matter if I die.
现在别争了！快点起来
Now, don't argue. Go on, get up.
不！长官！普威特不去 普威特决定待到苦果的最后
No, sir, not Prewitt. Prewitt stays right here to the bitter end.
好吧！我们一起留在这里
Okay, we'll stay together.
反正我也站不起来
I couldn't have got up anyway.
我惹了世界上最大的麻烦
I got the biggest troubles in the whole world.
世界级的吗？
In the whole world, huh?
都是因为爱
Take love.
你曾经见过爱情吗？
Did you personally ever see any of this love?
你不明白我的意思 这个女孩…
You don't understand what I mean. This girl, see...
她要求我成为…
...she wants me to become...
成为什么？  一名军官
Become what?   An officer.
你能想像我当军官的样子吗？
Can you see me as an officer?
可以！我能想像你当军官 你一定会是个好军官
Yeah, I can see you as an officer. You'd be a good officer.
你们两个比我有远见
You both can see more than I can see.
我不想当军官 我很喜欢现在这样
I don't want to be an officer. I'm happy where I am.
搞不好我会变成荷姆斯那种人
I might turn out to be a guy like Holmes.
你不希望我跟荷姆斯一样吧？
You wouldn't want me to be like Holmes, would you?
你会吗？
Well, would you?
男人应该做自己在行的事
A man should be what he can do.
你的女朋友呢？ 再告诉我一次她的芳名
How's your girl? What's her name again?
萝琳  对了！就是萝琳
Lorene.   Oh, yeah, Lorene.
我现在想起来了 好美的名字
I remember now. Beautiful name.
美极了
Beautiful.
你们两个愚蠢的疯家伙
You two dumb, crazy screwballs.
你们想找死吗？ 你们在这里做什么？
You trying to get killed? What're you doing here?
我的朋友普威特跟我 坐在这里讨论天气
My friend Prew and I are sitting here discussing the weather.
你的朋友？
Your friend, huh?
你得好好照顾这个人
You got to take care of this man.
荷姆斯迟早会整倒他
Holmes is bound to get him sooner or later.
他是陆军最棒的士兵
And he's the best soldier in the Army.
你们两个都晕头了
You both got rocks in your head.
安杰罗！安杰罗
Angelo, Angelo!
我就知道你一定在裘伊酒吧
I figured you'd be here at Choy's.
我办到了！普威特
I done it, Prew.
正如我所说的，我逃出来了 跟我所计划的一样
I escaped, just like I said. Just like I figured.
跳上了卡车，躲在防水布下面
In a back of a truck, under a tarp.
跟我所计划的一样 他们开车把我也载了出来
They rode me right out, just like I figured.
可惜离这儿一哩后，后挡泥板 就掉了，所以我跌到路上
Only the tailgate opened up about a mile back, and I fell out in the road.
你应该看我弹跳的样子 我应该有骨折才对
You should've seen me bounce. I must've broke something.
普威特，听我说
Prew, listen.
胖子做的，普威特
Fatso done it, Prew.
他很喜欢修理我
He likes to whack me in the gut.
一如往常，他问我会不会痛 然后我直接对着他吐口水
He asks me if it hurts and I spit at him like always.
只是昨天，情况很糟
Only yesterday, it was bad.
他不断的打我
He hit me, he hit me, he hit me.
我一定要出来，普威特 我一定要出来
I had to get out, Prew, I had to get out.
他们会送你回禁闭室  不，他们不会
They'll send you to the stockade.   No, they won't.
小心胖子！要小心胖子
Watch out for Fatso. Watch out for Fatso.
他想要修理你
He'll try to crack you.
如果他们把你关进单人牢里
If they put you in the hole...
千万别大叫，不要出声
...don't yell, don't make a sound.
否则当他们把你拉出来时 你还是在叫
You'll still be yelling when they come to take you out.
你只管躺在那里
Just lay there...
安安静静地躺在那里，普威特
...just lay there and be quiet, Prew.
他死了
He's dead.
我打赌那一定是普威特
I'll bet you that's Prew.
贾德森上士
Sergeant Judson?
你找我吗？
You want me?
是的，胖子
Yeah, Fatso.
我不喜欢那个外号 你找我有什么事吗？
I don't like that nickname. You want to see me about something?
我们找个角落好好谈谈
Let's step around the corner where we can talk.
你在生气什么吗？
Are you sore about something?
我不喜欢你弹琴的方式
I don't like the way you play the piano.
还记得马吉欧吗？  意大利佬？记得！那个泼猴
Remember Maggio?   The wop? Yeah, real tough monkey.
你杀了他  我有吗？
You killed him.   Did I?
如果我有，也是他咎由自取
If I did, he asked for it.
军队迟早会惩罚你
The Army's going to get you sooner or later.
可是在他们动手之前 我想先找你算算帐
But before they do, I want a piece of you myself.
我早知道了
I figured that.
看到这把刀了吗？ 是你先前威胁马吉欧时所用的
See this knife? It's the one you pulled on Maggio.
出了什么事？
What's happened?
没事了
It's all right.
别担心！别担心！我死不了
Don't worry. Don't worry. I ain't going to die.
仍然不知道谋杀 警卫上士的凶手是谁
全数到齐
All present and accounted for!
队伍解散
Company dismissed!
普威特还是没有出席
Prewitt's still absent.
已经三天了
Makes three days now.
你还要替他瞒多久？
How long will you carry him present?
我只是说说  那么就别再说了
I just mention it.   Well, don't mention it.
将军室
督察长展开调查…
"Upon these incidents, an investigation was made...
这些事件数个月
...by the inspector general over several months.
发现荷姆斯上尉 对普威特士兵残酷的罪行
Captain Holmes was found guilty of indefensible cruelty...
是无可辩解的
...to Private Prewitt.
其中包括唆使运用 未经许可的方式
This included the instigation of unauthorized tactics...
意图强迫他参加军团拳击赛
...to force him to join the inter regiment boxing team."
我正在等你回答  我无话可说，长官
I'm waiting for your reply.   I haven't any, sir.
荷姆斯，我在军队中 学习到的第一件事
Holmes, the first thing I learned in the Army...
就是军官要好好照顾部属
...was that an officer takes care of his men.
但这似乎是你最早忘记的事
It seems to be the first thing you forgot.
我很遗憾必须让你保留军职
I regret that we have to keep you in uniform...
直到军事法庭做出判决
...until a court martial is concluded.
若有办法能免除上军事法庭…
If there were any way to avoid a court martial, sir...
如果你愿意的话，将军 我倒有另一项选择
There is one alternative, general, if you are so disposed.
依照陆军规定辞职
A resignation for the good of the service under Army regulations.
下午就提出辞呈
Write a letter of resignation for this afternoon.
你愈快离开陆军 对大家愈有利
The quicker you're out of the Army, the better for everybody.
尤其是对陆军
Especially the Army.
就这样决定，荷姆斯
That's all, Holmes.
我很清楚事情的发展 也知道你有多么过份
I know what's been going on, how far some of you have been out of line.
如果你还想继任无委任状士官 就得赶紧努力
If you want to remain non coms, snap into it.
从现在开始 拳击已无法替任何人赢得官阶
From now on, no man's going to earn his stripes by boxing.
把那些扔掉  是的，长官
Get rid of those.   Yes, sir.
解散！
Dismissed.
关于葛罗维奇上士  是的，长官
About Sergeant Galovitch.   Yes, sir.
将他降级为葛罗维奇大兵
Bust him. He is now Private Galovitch.
派他去管厕所 你在笑什么？
Put him in charge of the latrine. What are you grinning at?
军团连长做了明智决定
The company commander made a wise decision, sir.
参谋部，罗斯上尉
Company G, Captain Ross.
请等一下！你的电话
Just a minute. It's for you.
谢谢你，长官
Thank you, sir.
是的，长官
Yes, sir.
是的，包裹已经到了
Yes, the parcel has already arrived.
什么？
What?
我必须见你一面 这件事很重要
I've got to see you. It's important.
好的，我想办法去 当然，没有问题
Okay, I'll get away somehow. Sure, that'd be fine.
我一小时之内赶到
I'll be there in about an hour.
他下礼拜就要被送回去
He's being sent back next week.
他要我跟他一起走 我们怎么办？
He wants me to go with him. What'll we do?
你何时能拿到派令？
When will you get your commission?
我没有申请 我是填好了但并没有签名
I didn't put it in. I filled it out, but I didn't sign it.
我把它拿出来许多次 但就是无法签名
I took it out a dozen times, but I couldn't sign it.
为什么？
Why?
这是我们的计划  我知道…
But it was the plan.   I know, I know.
你不能光说不做
You can't just say you'll do a thing and then not do it.
凯伦，听我说
Karen, listen to me.
你为什么不申请？ 你为什么不告诉我？
Why didn't you do it? Why didn't you tell me?
我马上回来
Be back in a minute.
对不起，我以为你是某人
Sorry, I thought you were somebody else.
我以为是我们军团的普威特
I thought it was that kid Prewitt from our company.
他迷上俱乐部的女孩
He got mixed up with a girl at the club.
他不假外出，可能有大麻烦
He's AWOL, probably in lots of trouble.
罗勃普威特是个疯狂的坏家伙
Robert E. Lee Prewitt, a crazy, no good...
凯伦，我不是当军官的料 我是个军人
Karen, I'm no officer. I'm an enlisted man.
别的事我都做不来 我一定只会装装样子
I can't be anything else. I'd be putting on an act.
我就是办不到 请不要问我原因
I just can't do it. Please don't ask me why.
我知道原因
I know why.
因为现在唐纳已经离开军队 所以你用不着去当军官
You don't have to become an officer now that Dana's out of the Army.
你就是不想娶我
You just don't want to marry me.
你已经结了婚 娶了陆军
You're already married. To the Army.
我是爱你的，凯伦
I love you, Karen.
我知道…
I know. I know.
我不希望你回到他身边  我也不想但我是在他身边
I don't want you to go back to him.   I don't want to, either, but I am.
我已经无能为力
There's nothing else for me to do.
对我们并没有好处 从来不可能有好结果
It's no good with us. It could never have been.
这样东躲西藏 磨耗了我们的感情
The hiding and the sneaking. It had to wear out.
再见了，上士
Goodbye, sergeant.
谢谢  这不是再见而是…
Thanks.   It ain't goodbye, it's...
总有一天我们会再某处重逢
We'll see each other again, somewhere.
我们当然会
Of course we will.
就在某处
Somewhere.
有消息了！已经登在内页
Here it is. They got it on the inside page already.
“谋杀詹姆士贾德森上士凶手 至今仍毫无线索”
"Still no clue in the fatal stabbing of Staff Sergeant James R. Judson."
你听见我说的吗？
Did you hear me?
你想创下新世界纪录吗？
You trying to set a new world's record?
是的，我就是这么打算
Yeah, as a matter of fact, I am.
纪念罗勃普威特
To the memory of Robert E. Lee Prewitt...
新世界纪录保持人
...holder of the new world's record.
还好吗？军士长  好极了
Everything all right, top?   Great.
这是在星期天的一顿美味餐 恭喜你了
A beautiful meal to put in front of a guy on Sunday. Congratulations.
从山上看下去真美  说得也是？
They look pretty over the mountains.   Don't they?
他们要轰炸车轮草原吗？
Are they dynamiting Wheeler Field?
真是有野心，是吧？ 星期天早上还不到八点钟
Mighty ambitious, huh? Sunday morning before 8:00.
日本战机正在轰炸车轮草原
The Japs are bombing Wheeler Field!
我看到红圆圈…
I seen the red circles on the...
到里面去！快一点！
Get inside! Hurry up, go!
这是真的，不是演习 日本人正在轰炸珍珠港
This is real, not a maneuver. The Japanese are bombing Pearl Harbor.
请留在室内！不要任意外出
Keep in your homes. Do not go out.
日本战正在轰炸 我方的海军及陆军设施
Japanese planes are bombing our Naval and Army installations.
好了！各位！安静！安静下来
All right, you guys, quiet down. Quiet. Quiet down!
士官们，快去拿机关枪和弹药 然后到屋顶上去
Non coms, get B A Rs and ammunition and get up on the roof.
韩德生，你负责装填子弹 动作快一点
Henderson, you're in charge of the loading detail. Get moving.
其他人快去拿步枪 然后回卧铺去，留在那里别动
The rest of you, get your rifle, go to your bunk and stay there.
我要你们留在那里
And I mean stay there!
闭嘴！
Shut up!
你们到外面会被击中 你们有机会成为英雄
You'll be shot outside! You'll get a chance to be heroes.
在夜晚来临之前 日本人就会坐在你的大腿上！快
There'll be Japs in your lap before night. Now get moving!
去煮一壶咖啡 等一下！煮一桶咖啡
Go make a pot of coffee. Wait a minute, a barrel of coffee!
没有命令我不能发给弹药
I can't issue ammo without an order.
可是上尉不在营里  很抱歉
But the captain ain't here!   I'm sorry.
怎么回事？列瓦  我奉命如此！陆军规定…
What's the matter, Leva?   I got orders! Army regulations say...
你瞎了吗？把钥匙拿来  我奉命如此
You blind? Give me the keys!   I got orders!
我会看着你得到勋章！冲开  我警告过你
I'll see you get a medal! Bust it.   I warned you!
别出去！你会没命的  快点穿衣服！你会着凉的
Don't go out there! You'll die!   Get dressed. You'll catch cold.
快帮他们处理弹药 把那个东西放在那边
Help them with this ammo! Put that stuff over there.
小心开火！瞄准飞机前方
Watch your fire and lead those planes!
他正在吹“骑兵突袭乐”
He's blowing the "Cavalry Charge"!
他们来了！各位
Here they come, boys!
我打中他了！我打中他了  我打中他了
I got him! I got him!   I got him.
入侵的危机仍然存在
The danger of invasion still exists.
雪菲德部队在数小时内移防 并已就滩头位置
Schofield units moved out within hours and have manned beach positions.
这不是演习！这是真正打仗
This is no maneuver. This is the real McCoy.
小心榴霰弹！快找掩护
Look out for falling shrapnel. Keep under cover.
将实施灯火管制及宵禁
Blackout and curfew restrictions will be enforced.
请留在家中并不要使用电话
Stay in your homes. Don't use the phone.
我们传播所有资讯…
We'll relay all information...
我们捐血了
We've been giving blood.
简直混乱极了  库希欧有房子遭到轰炸
It's a madhouse!   A house got bombed on Kuhio.
一间杂货店被夷为平地 有对夫妇因而丧生
And a drugstore smashed flat! A man and his wife were killed.
请各位注意 注意听好并保持镇静
Your attention, please. Listen carefully and keep calm.
入侵的危机仍然存在
The danger of invasion still exists.
进行轰炸的飞机 已确认属日方所有
And the planes have been identified as Japanese...
他们以为在向谁挑衅？
Who do they think they're fighting?
他们正在对抗 世界上最精良的陆军
They're fighting the best Army in the world.
你要上哪儿去？  我必须回去…
Where are you going?   I gotta get back to...
我必须回部队去  部队？为什么？
I gotta get back to the company.   The company? But why?
为什么？  不可以！你还没有复原
Why?   But you can't. You're not well yet.
你会被关到禁闭室
And you'll be thrown in the stockade.
他们需要所有能用的人手
They need every guy they can get.
但你的伤口会裂开 他们会知道是你杀了那个士官
But your side will open up. They'll find out you killed that soldier.
只要我向部队报到 他们就会照顾我的
Once I report in to the company, they'll take care of me.
你绝对到不了的 到处都有人在巡逻
You'll never make it! There's patrols all over!
我到得了！我知道捷径
I'll make it. I know a shortcut.
留到天亮再说吧！ 或许你会改变心意
Stay till morning. Maybe you'll change your mind.
普威特，不要走 我会照你的话去做
Oh, Prew, don't go! I'll do anything you want!
我们可以一起回美国 甚至我们可以结婚
We can go back to the States together. We can even get married.
若你走了，我再也见不到你  对不起
Lf you go, I'll never see you again.   I'm sorry.
你为什么想回去？
Why do you want to go back?
陆军根本视你如粪土…
The Army treated you like dirt...
经常殴打你，还害你朋友丧命
...gave you an awful going over, got your friend killed!
你为什么想回去？
Why do you want to go back?
我为什么想回去？ 因为我是军人
Why do I want to go back? I'm a soldier.
军人！一个常备兵！一个陆军！ 一个准备当兵三十年的人！
A soldier! A regular. From the regular Army! A 30 year man!
外面正在实施灯火管制 所以我得把灯关掉
I gotta turn off the lights because of the blackout outside.
山上有伞兵降落  我并不担心他们
Parachutists landed in the hills.   They don't worry me.
我担心的是破坏份子  我打赌他们一定遍布全岛
Saboteurs is what worries me.   I bet they're all over the islands.
不要动！
Halt!
你认识这个人吗？上士  是的，长官
Do you know this man, sergeant?   Yes, sir.
他没有任何身分证明 他们找到有他名字的卡片
He didn't have any regular I.D. They found a card with his name.
好像是俱乐部的会员证 新国会俱乐部
Seems to be a membership in a club. The New Congress Club.
你最好处理一下
You'd better take care of this.
他是你的朋友吗？
Was he your friend?
他一定是想回到海滩上的部队
He must've been trying to reach our company up the beach.
那么为什么他不停止？
Then why didn't he halt?
他是死脑筋但却是个好军人
He was a hard head, but he was a good soldier.
他是我认识的所有人中 最爱陆军的
He loved the Army more than anyone else I knew.
我明白了，很遗憾，上士
I see. I'm sorry, sergeant.
你就是不能从善如流
You just couldn't play it smart.
不过是要你打拳罢了 可是你这个死脑筋就是不肯
All you had to do is box, but no, not you, you hard head.
好笑的是，今年没有拳击冠军
Funny thing is, there won't be a boxing championship this year.
没有看过死人吗？ 把尸体抬出去
Ain't you ever seen a dead man? Let's get this body out of here!
真美，是吧？
It's very beautiful, isn't it?
我想这是我此生见过 最美的一个地方
I think it's the most beautiful place I ever saw in my life.
我几乎能看见我工作的地方
I can almost see where I worked from here.
听说有个传说
There's a legend.
如果花环漂向海岸 表示你还会再回来
If they float in toward shore, you'll come back.
如果是向外漂，你就不会回来
If they float out, you won't.
我不会再回来了
I won't come back.
我的未婚夫在十二月七日被杀
You see, my fiancé was killed on December 7 th.
真是遗憾  他原是个轰炸机飞行员
Oh, I'm sorry.   He was a bomber pilot.
当他把飞机滑到停机坪边缘…
He taxied his plane to the edge of the apron...
日军直接击中他
...and the Japs made a direct hit on it.
或许你曾在报上看过消息
Maybe you read about it in the papers.
他获授银星勋章
He was awarded the Silver Star.
军方将勋章送给他母亲 她写信给我，要我保留它
They sent it to his mother. She wrote me she wanted me to have it.
她真好
That's very fine of her.
南方人都很好
They're very fine people. Southern people.
他以某位将军的名字为名
He was named after a general.
罗勃
Robert E. Lee...
普威特
...Prewitt.
谁？
Who?
罗勃普威特
Robert E. Lee Prewitt.
真是个愚蠢的老名字吧？
Isn't that a silly old name?